Привет, that means hello in Russian.
Welcome to привет русский episode 19 for May 4th, 2026.
I'm Olya, and today we're going to learn some really fun Russian word.
Ready?
Why a hale?
That means let's go.
Our word of the day is cosmos.
Cosmos.
Repeat after me.
This word means space.
It sounds exactly like the English word cosmos.
That is your memory hook, to remember it easily.
Let's use it in a sentence.
Я изучаю космос.
That means I study space.
Repeat after me.
Я изучаю космос.
This word means space.
It sounds exactly like the English word.
Well done!
Hey, let's learn some more words about space.
The word for star is звезда.
звезда.
Repeat after me.
It means star.
Think of the sparkling z sound for bright star, twinkling in the sky.
Now that you know звезда, let's learn cometa.
cometa.
Repeat after me.
This means comet.
It sounds just like the English word comet.
Next, the word for planet is planet.
Planeta.
Repeat after me.
It means planet.
Земля это planet.
That means Earth is a planet.
Repeat after me.
Земля это planet.
The word for rocket is rocket.
Rocket.
Repeat after me.
It means rocket.
Rocket.
it calls condhoot.
Rocket calls condhoot.
Rocket...
Rocket calls condhoot happiness...
Looking for the target I want to make in 2019 a lot more people do not know.
на солнце, сонце, репит автормии солнце, солнце, it means sun, солнце в небе,
that means the sun is in the sky. репит автормии солнце в небе, солнце в небе,
next is nebo, небо, небо репит авторми, небо, небо, this means sky.
Небоглубое, датминс, доскай из блю, репет авторми,
Налет слух от сам граммор, викинуйся, я вижу, тутал забоуно в сиинспейс.
Я, минс, ай, дежу, минс, айси.
Со я вижу, звезду, минс, айси, стар.
Я вижу кометы, в небе, минс айси, комет, в доска.
This is Summary English, I see the star, but Russian does not use A or D.
The word ending might change a little when it is the object you see.
Practice saying it slowly.
Я вижу, звезду.
Now you can say, я вижу, но Луна.
That means I see the moon.
Great work!
Russia has a proud history of space exploration that inspires many families.
The first person I traveled to space was a Russian cosmonaut Yuri Gagarin in the 1960s.
Children often learn history in school.
Looking at the stars, I remember the fever of activity in the Parmenia rations during the lockdown in March.
Now it is time to practice.
If you are a kid, go outside the night and look at the sky.
Point to the moon and say, это Луна.
Это Луна.
That means this is the moon.
Then point to the star and say, это звезда.
For adults practice, я вижу, как мать в небе.
That means I see a comet in the sky.
Tremicking one sentence with a three new word from today's list.
Now here is something really cool about one of today's words.
Want to know a secret about comet?
Did you know that Russian word comet and the English word comet
are actually the same word.
They both come from the ancient Greek word cometis, which meant long hair.
This word started in ancient Greece to describe the comet's tail that looks like flowing hair.
It travelled through Latin as comet and then spread to English and Russian when scientists began studying the sky centuries ago.
But be careful, although it sounds the same in Russian it is pronounced cometa with a stress on the middle part.
Next time you see a comet, remember, it is cousins of the Russian comet.
They both come from the Greek word for hair restart.
That connection is your secret short, as to remember it forever.
Молодец.
That means we'll done.
Remember, every expert start as a beginner practicing today's words out loud.
Even just once and you'll be amazed how fast you'll learn.
See you next time.
Papa.
That's Russian far by.
This podcast is curated by Patrick, but generated using AI voice synthesis of my voice.
The primary reason to do this is I unfortunately don't have the time to be consistent with generating all the content and wanted to focus on creating consistent and regular episodes for all the themes that I enjoy.
And I hope others do as well.